# **AARON APPLETON**

Email: aaronappleton@gse.harvard.edu

Phone: +44.737.535.8027 LinkedIn: aaronappleton.com Portfolio: aaronappleton.github.io I love working with cross-disciplinary teams through the full product development lifecycle to discover, design and deliver educational products that address new growth opportunities, generate end-user value, and lead to transformational learning experiences.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Learning Experience Design Product Management Product Strategy Learning Sciences Educational Game Design



# **EXPERIENCE**

Founder & Chief Design Officer

Harvard Innovation Labs | Limehouse

Cambridge, Massachusetts 2020 - Present

Learning Experience Design Lead **ALU Education** 

Mauritius | Nairobi | Johannesburg | Kigali | Dakar 2017 - 2020

Science Department Chair & Game Designer NYC Department of Education | Quest to Learn New York, New York 2014 - 2017

Founding Vice Principal & Science Teacher Kampala Diplomatic School

Kampala, Uganda 2011 - 2014 Selected for Harvard Innovation Lab's venture program where I'm incubating a startup called Limehouse with five other team members.

• Limehouse is the education metaverse — a three-sided marketplace that connects learners, educators, and 3D artists through creating learning experiences in playable worlds.

ALU has been dubbed "the university of the future" by CNN, and one of the 50 most innovative organizations in in the world by Fast Company. We have over \$350 million in funding, and are training entrepreneurial leaders for Africa.

• Oversaw the design and delivery of our School of Wildlife Conservation's full product portfolio, supporting growth to 5 countries and over \$3 million in revenue.

Quest to Learn is the world's first school to be built around the principles of game design. The school was founded with funding from the Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation and MacArthur Foundation.

- Led design and delivery for the founding game-based curriculum for all science subjects.
- Chaired the science department of 6 teachers and average of 140 students.

Kampala Diplomatic School is the flagship institution in a pan-African network of schools across Sudan, Chad, and Botswana. We primarily serve students from families in the diplomatic community.

• Led a 12 person teaching staff and the design of the school's founding curriculum during a period of 59% growth in student enrollment.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Education
Harvard University
Cambridge, Massachusetts

Cross-Registered
Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)
Cambridge, Massachusetts

Master of Arts in Teaching (Earth System Science)

City University of New York - Brooklyn College

Brooklyn, New York

Improv 101 & Improv 201 Upright Citizens Brigade New York, New York Candidate in the **Technology, Innovation, and Education masters program**. Coursework is split between the Graduate School of Education, the Graduate School of Design, the School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, MIT, and Harvard Business School.

Cross-registered coursework for my M.Ed. degree through MIT. Courses include: Design and Development of Games for Learning, Game Design, and Playful and Social Interaction Design.

I was a science fellow with the **NYC Teaching Fellows**, which is a selective program that aims to improve the quality of education in NYC. Fellows go through an intensive pre-service training program and pursue a funded master's degree while teaching at a New York City school.

Learned how to perform long-form improv. Classes included topics such as how to use "yes-and," active listening, and playing at the top of your intelligence.

## **AWARDS**

Segal AmeriCorps Education Award Corporation for National & Community Service Washington, D.C. 2015

Science Fellowship Fund for Teachers

Buton, Indonesia 2017

Science Fellowship

Earthwatch Institute

Tahoe National Forest, California 2016

Science Fellowship **Ecology Project International** 

Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming 2016

\$5,775 award for leadership excellence in education.

\$5,000 grant to work with an international group of field biologists to calculate carbon biomass in forests on the Indonesian island of Buton, to be used for carbon trading markets.

Fully funded research grant that partners science educators with ecology researchers to collect and analyze data on the the carbon sequestration capacity of meadow's in California's Sierra Nevada mountains.

Fully funded research grant that partners science educators with ecology researchers to collect and analyze data on the wildlife dynamics of cougars in Yellowstone National Park.

**LINKS** 





